Binuka Witharana

Profile

A dedicated and reliable Laboratory Technician with excellent organisation skills and education background as a Biochemistry Graduate. Previous experience as a Medical Assistant with demonstrated commitment to providing excellent patient care. Analytical, detail-oriented with strong time management abilities with proven success of managing multiple patients daily. A fast learner with a great work ethic and the ability to work independently or with others.

Employment History

Laboratory Technician (Asbestos) at ALS Environmental, Springvale

April 2021 — June 2021

- Preparation of samples for analysis (e.g., signing off work-orders, creating work-order sheets, drying samples in oven, accurately weighing, recording and bagging samples according to size and work-order, maintaining and updating daily samples lists).
- Adhering to a high standard of safety at all times when handling samples and maintaining a clean and safe work area.
- Organizing and prioritizing work to complete assignments in a timely, efficient manner.
- Liaising with client services and other laboratory departments through phone and email.
- Working well independently and on a team to solve problems.

Medical Assistant at SureCell PRP Medical Clinic, Malvern

September 2019 — October 2020

- Fulfilled Medical Assistant duties at a fast-paced private PRP clinic
- Monitored and recorded 10+ patients daily (e.g., obtained patients' vital signs, recorded their medical condition and prepared them for assessment by physicians and nurses).
- Venepuncture and PRP treatment (i.e., centrifuging and extracting plasma from patients' blood) in a well-maintained aseptic environment
- Liaising with patients, health professionals and stakeholders through phone, email and letters
- Assisted nurses and physicians during patient treatment and care.
- Sterilized and set up treatment rooms, restocked rooms and monitored medical supply inventory
- Delivered high standard of patient care on a daily basis to all patients who arrived at the clinic

Customer Service Representative at Salvos Stores, Cranbourne North

September 2018 — January 2019

- Provided excellent customer service through product knowledge and shopping assistance
- Maintained the department through cleaning, organizing, and stocking merchandise.
- Assisted other sales associates with customer matters, stocking of merchandise, and organizing products

Line Cook at Gobble N' Go, Wodonga

June 2015 — July 2017

Details

0481209630 binuka.witharana@gmail.com

Skills

Customer Service
Interpersonal Communication
Highly organized and efficient
Effective Time Management
Collaboration & Teamwork
Critical thinking and problem
solving
Flexibility and Adaptability
Microsoft Office
Laboratory Skills

Languages

Sinhala

- Provided optimal customer service to all patrons to help encourage return patronage.
- Prepared an organized station before the start of service each day.
- · Cleaned kitchen and organized cooking utensils.
- Safely stored food items and kept inventories.
- · Handled food with cleanliness and care.
- Maintained a professional and positive demeanour at all times.

Car Mechanic Shop Assistant at Peter Sains Motor Workshop, Bright

September 2012 — January 2013

- Worked as a positive and hardworking team member in the busy auto-body shop.
- Filled out vehicle identification notices and sorting new products.
- Maintained the cleanliness and order of workstations and restocked supplies

Laboratory assistant at Monash University, Parkville

July 2012 — August 2012

- · Accurately prepared sample and calibrated equipment prior to sessions
- Appropriately cleaned laboratory equipment following each session
- Properly disposed of contaminated and bio-hazard materials according to laboratory safety regulations

Education

Coding Bootcamp, Monash University

August 2021 — Present

Graduate Diploma of Human Nutrition, Deakin University

March 2020 — Present

Bachelor of Science - Biochemistry, Monash University, Clayton

March 2015 — June 2019

Major: Biochemistry and Minor: Business Management

Laboratory techniques experience in Immunofluorescence Microscopy, Western Blot, SDS-PAGE Gel Electrophoresis and PCR.

Victorian Certificate of Education, Bright P-12 College, Bright

February 2014 — November 2014

Voluntary Experience

The Royal Melbourne Show, Melbourne

September 2019 — September 2019

Distributing showground maps, answering inquirers from show goers, directing show goers to events.

Wodonga Council ANZAC Day Parade, Wodonga

April 2019 — April 2019

Handing out novelties before the parade, direct crowd to parade venue and assist in wreath laying ceremony.

Salvos Store Assistant, Cranbourne North

June 2018 — January 2019

Stocking items in appropriate areas, Inventory, cleaning, preparation and pricing of items ready to be sold in the store. Greeting and assisting customers with items and purchases.

References

References available upon request